The lightening of God moves in the midst of the congregation,
dispelling all shades of darkness
through the medium of the Morning Water used by the evangelists
who have been sent by Prophet T.B. Joshua.
Remember! Where the light of God is, darkness has no hiding place.
Let us watch as the darkness in the life of this boy
and his family are dispelled in Jesus' name.
Manifestation of Evil Spirits
Fire!
Fire, in the name of Jesus! Who are you? Who are you in this body?
Manifestation of Evil Spirits
Fire, in the name of Jesus!
Who are you?
What have you done to him?
Speak out, in the name of Jesus Christ!
What have you done to his family?
I destroyed them.
How did you destroy them?
My name is Destruction.
Destruction, how have you destroyed the family?
How have you destroyed this man?
Speak, in the name of Jesus Christ!
I don't allow them to prosper.
You don't allow them to prosper - how?
I ruin their businesses.
You ruin their businesses? What else?
I close all doors.
What have you done to his future and his education?
He's a star.
But that star belongs to me.
Look here!
Who are these people here?
Who are these people next to you?
The aunty.
Madam, you are very welcome.
Who is he to you?
He's my nephew.
He is your nephew?
Yes.
What can you say about his behaviour?
There is no progress in the family.
He stopped going to school.
He will tell them he's going to school.
He took the school fees and ate them.
He would say he was going and go to his friend's house and stay there.
He did't take his exams.
He collected money for assignments but didn't do the assignments.
He will come and tell us that he went to school.
Somebody from the school called.
"Do you know that Jeffery has not been coming to school? Is there any problem?"
We were all shocked.
I had to take it upon myself to go to school and found out that he was never in school.
When we asked him, he told us that he was going to his friend's house to smoke
and that he used the money to gamble.
His father's business locked up; there was no progress in the family.
Today is our happiest day.
I just bless God for helping me bring him to church today.
He came; I am so happy that God visited our family.
Amen! We thank God.
So, who is he to you?
He is my cousin.
My aunty has said it all; he has all the addictions - smoking, drinking, the school issues.
She has said it all.
We see that it is just the evil spirit inside him.
Ministration Of The Morning Water In Jesus' Name
Fire, in the name of Jesus!
Speak out! How many of you are inside this body?
How many of you demons are inside this body?
Fire, in the name of Jesus!
How many?
We are many.
Who is the second person?
Confusion.
How have you, Confusion, affected his education?
Manifestation Of Evil Spirits
You demon, how did you enter him?
Through friends.
What was he doing with his friends that allowed you to enter?
Manifestation Of Evil Spirits
He liked to party.
What did they use to do at those parties?
They drink, smoke and do all sorts of evil.
When he smokes and drinks, what happens to him?
Everything goes to his head.
Manifestation Of Evil Spirits
Right now, through this medium of the Morning Water sent by Prophet T.B. Joshua,
it's time for you to go, in the name of Jesus Christ!
You are free, in Jesus' name.
Thank You, Lord.
Set Free In Jesus' Name
Rise up.
Congratulations, the Lord has set you free.
Thank You, Jesus!
Thank You, Jesus! We are grateful. My family is grateful. Thank You.
We thank God Almighty, but we know that it was the evil spirit
that was causing him to do all this smoking and drinking.
So we advice you, sir, make the Bible the standard for your life
so that you would be able to maintain this deliverance, in the name of Jesus Christ.
In Jesus' Name!
Fire, in the name of Jesus Christ!
Fire!
So right now, through this medium of the Morning Water,
you demons, it is time for you to go, in the name of Jesus Christ!
Out, in Jesus Christ' name!
You are free, in the name of Jesus Christ.
Deliverance In Jesus' Name Through Ministration Of The Morning Water
Set Free In Jesus' Name
Thank You, Jesus! I'm free, in Jesus' name!
My family is free!
Thank You, Lord! We are free. Our family is free.
Thank You, Lord Jesus! I'm free today!
TESTIMONY TIME
My name is Jeffery.
Besides me are my father, my mum and my aunty.
Jeffery & Family - Nigeria
Go ahead with your testimony.
Emmanuel! (God with us - Matthew 1:23)
My testimony goes like this.
When I was 18 years of age, I went to my friend's house and he asked me if I was hungry.
I gave him money to buy noodles which he prepared.
Inside the noodles, I saw this green leaf - it was very long; I wondered what it was.
He said that it was just thyme.
I thought it was fine since we were all going to eat the food together.
Then, we started eating the food and I noticed that I was acting strangely.
I took it as nothing because we were all feeling the same way.
I asked him what he had put in the food and he replied it was just thyme,
that I should just eat and be happy.
It got to a point where it was too much for me - my head felt very light.
Then, he said it was time for me to go home. He took me to the house.
On my way, we branched to the pharmacy and he got me a particular medication
used to clear your eyes when you are very high, when your eyes are very red
so that people wouldn't know you were high.
You could just act all cool and stay calm.
After all that, the next day, I met him again and asked, "Can I get an upgrade?
Instead of eating it, could I do something else with it?"
He said, "Sure I could smoke it."
He showed me how to roll the weed and I started smoking it from then until I entered university.
While in university, I met some friends.
They told me that they smoked, drank and did drugs and asked me what I did.
I said I just smoked and they said it was fine and that we should smoke together.
We left lectures, went to the back of the school and started smoking.
Then, a brother ordered drugs and I started taking painkillers from then.
After the painkillers, they introduced me to cocaine but I refused to take it,
codeine and other stuff.
All this happened while I was in university.
With this, I stopped going to school and I started looking for money to buy drugs
because I needed drugs to stay high and focused.
I had been deceived that I was taking drugs to get focused.
It is a big deceit because you cannot achieve what you want to achieve when you are high.
It is not possible because it wastes your time.
Once you decided, "I will smoke today", that was all. I would get high and life continued.
I smoked every day.
In the morning, when I woke up, I smoked.
I would take a bath. Then, after food, I would smoke.
In the afternoon, I would smoke.
Every single day, before going to school, I smoked;
I always got high before I went for lectures.
During the lectures, it was either I was sleeping or chatting with my friends.
I just focused away from my schooling.
With that, I started stealing.
I started stealing my parents' stuff and selling things from the house like my parents' jewellery.
I started taking what was not mine just to buy drugs and get high.
It was something that I could not stop.
I was looking for a better way of stealing.
I met this friend of mine who told me that he could help me join a cult.
I would get boys who would be at my back and I would be under them for protection.
I told the guy that I was not sure about it and wanted to think about it for a while.
He kept on asking me that question but I would always dodge him,
to the extent that I stopped going to the guy's place but each time he saw me on the road,
he would ask me what my answer was to what we had talked about.
I would tell him that I was still thinking about it, that the next time we met I would talk about it.
I felt that being in a cult was not really necessary because I had my parents.
Fine, they might say I was too soft or something.
I could just stay on my own without being in a cult, going for robberies
or doing whatever they did.
I avoided the guy.
The spirit brought in confusion and made me do away with my school fees.
It made me destroy my parents' business and took away the glory of the family.
I went for parties where we would scam people over the internet.
Actually, the spirit made me to hate school and everything about reading.
I never saw myself reading; I was not the reading type.
I just didn't like school.
Now, tell us how you finally came to The SCOAN for your deliverance.
After watching Emmanuel TV for a long while, I was very close to my aunt and I told her
how I had been seeing people being delivered on Emmanuel TV and I needed deliverance too.
That morning, I was begging her although I don't like going to church,
I begged her to take me to church. She said fine and that I should dress up.
Then, she brought me here.
While the Morning Water was being ministered, I wasn't myself.
I got lost in a trance.
After your deliverance, what can you say about your new life?
My life has been peaceful ever since.
I don't smoke anymore.
I don't have the urge to take drugs anymore.
I am just happy with myself.
I just feel good right now.
Thanks to God, I am happy that I am delivered.
Shall we put our hands together for Jesus.
Jeffery & Family - Morning Water Testimony
We would like to listen to your parents. Let's hear from your dad.
Sir, tell us your name and whom the young man is to you
and what you have to say concerning his previous character.
Emmanuel!! - (God with us - Matthew 1:23)
My name is Emmanuel.
The boy standing here is my son, Jeffery.
Jeffery used to be a very brilliant son of mine.
All this began when he entered into the final year of secondary school.
A boy that is inclined scientifically, does a lot of things with computers and telephones.
Most of the time, when I have issues to do with my laptop
or anything that has to do with computers, what I do is call him to put me through.
I was just very happy the way he was going but all of a sudden,
when he wanted to choose the subjects for his final year in secondary school,
which ought to have been sciences, the boy automatically changed to art subjects.
I asked him if he had been doing art subjects before and he said no but that he loved doing art.
He said that art was his desire and that he loved to act and draw -
that was what he wanted to do.
I was surprised - a boy who was doing very well in his academics in science subjects,
all of a sudden decided to change to arts.
The teachers at his school called me and asked if I was aware of what my son wanted to do.
I said yes and that I had asked him but one thing that I would never do,
was to stop him from doing the course that he wanted to do.
What I would do was just to ask him to confirm that this was what he wanted to do.
Then, I would back him up.
That was what I did in that aspect.
I kept asking questions but he said that was what he wanted to do.
I told him not to worry, that I would back him up
and that whatever he did, he should come out to be the best.
He started out that way.
When he got admission into university, we asked him to try as much as possible to live on campus
But unfortunately, he couldn't get accommodation on campus;
so, he had to come from home.
Every day, Jeffery would collect money from me to go to school.
One thing I observed at that time was that he went out every day
but would come back between 9:30pm - 10:00pm, every day.
Sometimes, he would sleep and sleep.
At around 10 o'clock, I would go to his room and asked him if he was still sleeping
and if he wasn't going to school or having lectures that day.
He would tell me, "Daddy, my lecture is in the afternoon".
I would ask why other kids were in school while only he attended class in the afternoon.
I was a little bit scared and angry with him.
This continued.
It was to the extent that one day, I saw him as he came in and his eyes were red.
I tried to find out what had happened to him.
He said that he was okay, only that he was having a slight headache
which was why his eyes were red.
I prayed with him and told him that whenever he comes back, he should come and see me
so that I would be able to know exactly what was wrong with him.
But one thing Jeffery did was never to come back to me at any point in time.
He tried to keep away from me.
Whenever he came back so late, he would never bother to come upstairs and see me.
He would just go to his room and that was it.
Sometimes, when you put food on the table, Jeffery would not eat.
The next day, the way you left that food was how it would be.
I began to ask what the problem was - did he have someone taking care of him in school?
He would say he was okay, he was fine. That was how Jeffery had been.
I noticed a lot of changes but the only thing was that he never told the truth.
At any point in time, when you asked him a question, he had one thing or the other to tell you.
As a deacon in my church, I always told him that the truth of the matter was that it is good for you
to be truthful in life so that somebody would be able to help you when you had problems.
But as a man, when you grow in the life of not telling the truth often,
nobody will know when you have needs, problems - people will never take you serious.
That was one thing I tried to minister to him but I found that at any point in time,
Jeffery kept on telling lies, which is not of God. I always cautioned him.
But to God be the glory, I was very happy that he was delivered.
One thing that I want to tell people is that - my son, Jeffery used to be a nice boy.
Sometimes, when he went out with friends, he didn't even bother to know who his friends were.
I would say that assuming I had followed him up as a parent,
I would have known who his friends were.
It would have been better for him to bring his friends home and let us talk to them
and know exactly what they were into.
Some of them might not be the best for him but at least, I would had been able to guide him
and say, "This friend is not good for you to walk with, do this,
look for people that have the fear of God so that they can help increase your spiritual life".
But Jeffery never brought his friends home; his friends were always outside.
Whenever he wanted to go out, he went out;
whenever he wanted to come back, he came back.
Whenever we asked him questions, he went straight to tell us, "I am fine".
Who are your friends? He will say my friends are there.
He said, "Daddy, I will never fail you" up 'til today, he had failed the whole family.
Praise the Lord!
We thank God for the deliverance your son has received but we just want to ask you,
there was a time you said that he used to sleep and kept telling you that he had lectures in the afternoon.
Did you inquire from anybody whether he was actually in school or not?
Yes. Whenever Jeffery slept and I went to wake him up for school,
I had people that I thought I had handed Jeffery over to at school to look after him.
One of them was a lecturer there.
I said, "Listen, my friend, you are there. I believe as a father, you are there with Jeffery.
Please, guide Jeffery and teach Jeffery the right thing to do".
Also, Jeffery's immediate younger sister was at the same school as him.
That one was always very serious and never came home.
With Jeffery, I had tried as much as possible to give him a reason to stay in school and read.
He preferred to come from the house.
Every morning I go out to my business and come back as late as six or seven in the evening.
By then, he would have gone out to school.
I was not monitoring him the way I ought to have because every morning, I go out for my business.
He too, pretended to go to school, but he never did.
That was the problem.
Also, sir, did you ask how he was doing in school from those people you handed him over to?
Sometimes when I asked him, he said Jeffery was doing well.
Also, his sister always told me that Jeffery was fine but that the only thing was that
his friends were complaining that Jeffery did not attend lectures.
That was when we knew that things had got so bad.
When I asked Jeffery if he went to school, he would say that he went to school.
I would ask, "How was school?" He would say that it was beautiful, fine.
I would ask him where his books were.
At least, somebody who went to school was supposed to have handouts,
textbooks and other reading materials.
Jeffery never read.
At any point in time, when you asked him a question, he would say, "Daddy, don't worry.
This is a scientific world now; everything is on the systems. We go to the systems to read"
and he said that he was going to make it better.
Up until now, he did not read his books but I thank God that since his deliverance,
Jeffery stays at home instead of always going out.
I went to him and asked, "Jeffery, what do you want to do?"
He would say, "Daddy, I want to relax or look at one thing or the other".
This makes me so happy now.
To God be the glory.
We just want to hear from you, sir, what effort have you made to find a solution to the problem of your son?
As a deacon in my church, I mostly have pastors as my friends.
Most of the time, some of them come to the house to pray for us.
Whenever we needed them, they always came.
They always told me that Jeffery had an issue, a problem
but no one could really tell what it was.
I took it up myself and fasted most of the time.
Even the week that he came for deliverance, I was fasting for five days because of him.
I had tried all that I could to make this boy change.
When I prayed, he didn't even seem to understand why one should pray.
Sometimes, I called him to come but to him, it seemed I was a time waster.
To him, being in the presence of God was time wasting.
Jeffery never even followed me.
Whenever I called him to come to church, what he would do was to run to the toilet.
He would either tell me that he was stooling, his tummy was disturbing him.
He would stay there; I would sound my car horn and shout but he would never come out.
Out of annoyance, I would leave him and go to church.
And finally, he came to The SCOAN.
By the grace of God, he was delivered from this spirit that gave him several bad habits.
What changes have you noticed ever since he received deliverance here at The SCOAN?
Praise the Lord!
Since Jeffery came for deliverance, his life has totally changed.
One thing I noticed was this: Jeffery never woke up early to do the things he ought to do
without me forcing him.
Since his deliverance, when he wakes up, he goes straight to the parlour,
opens the windows and sweeps.
He goes to the cars, even the ones I don't want to use, and washes them for me,
which he had never done.
As old as Jeffery is, one always had to tell him, "Do this", before he did something
at any point in time.
He never took the initiative to do something on his own.
Since his deliverance, he has been so calm; he stays at home
and has not been going out for a few days now.
Things have really changed.
When I speak with him, the way he responds to the questions tells me that
something has happened in his life.
Praise the Lord!
Shall we put our hands together for Jesus.
Emmanuel & Family - Morning Water Testimony
How is his prayer life now?
Previously, when I called Jeffery to get up to pray and do our morning devotion,
everybody would be out but Jeffery would not join us.
But now, when we just start upstairs - he is downstairs - when he hears my voice,
he wakes up by himself and joins us in prayer.
Now, he is more focused.
I have heard him pray out loud but before, he could not.
When you asked him to pray, he would just be murmuring.
I would say, "What are you murmuring?
Why not voice out and let me hear what you are saying? Pray out so that we can hear you well".
But then, he didn't do that and you could not force him.
Whatever you asked him to do, he would choose to do what he wanted.
But now, he prays out loud and I have heard him praising God,
singing to praise and worship His holy name.
Praise the name of the Lord!
Let's put your hands together for Jesus!
Morning Water Testimony
We believe your wife has one or two things to say concerning this deliverance
and this testimony.
Madam, tell us your name and who the brother is to you
and what you have to say.
My name is Phillipias.
The boy standing beside me is my son, Jeffery.
Phillipias & Family - Morning Water Testimony
What can you say about his deliverance?
I thank God that after his deliverance, my son is calm. His character has changed.
He is always indoors; he's not going outside.
Emmanuel! (God with us - Matthew 1:23)
Jeffery & Family - Morning Water Testimony
Let's put our hands together for Jesus!
We also want to hear from the aunty that brought Jeffery here for deliverance.
Sister, ever since he received deliverance, I believe you have seen
one or two changes in his life.
Tell us what you can say about Jeffery now.
Emmanuel! (God with us - Matthew 1:23)
My name is Promise.
Looking at Jeffery now, he looks fresh. That is one of the things.
Unlike when he was dry and I kept asking what was drying him up.
You would see those veins; they would just shoot out like that.
He would always frown his face but now, he is happy.
He said, "Aunty, God has visited me" and God has visited him.
Praise God!
Indeed, God has visited this family and to God be the glory
they are here to share the wonderful testimony of the power of God
through this medium of Morning Water.
We just want to hear your advice to viewers.
We would start with the father first.
Sir, tell us the advice you have for viewers all over the world.
Emmanuel! (God with us - Matthew 1:23)
The advice I have for viewers watching us this morning -
I would say that it is not all just about having children
but I would advise every parent to create time for their children.
Monitor them, who their friends are, know how they move.
Don't only send them to school and say, "Yes, I have paid their school fees,
I have given them all they required".
You, as a father, you, as a mother have to create time to visit them and know what they are doing -
Whether they are really attending lectures and still doing that which they ought to do.
Most especially, as children of God, parents who were brought up in the Christian way,
try to make sure that your ward belongs to a Christian fellowship on campus.
That is the only thing that will help them in life.
I can remember when I was in university, I had my prayer groups
and every day, we were involved in one programme or the other.
But these children never do that.
The duty of parents is this: make sure you monitor your ward,
make sure you know whom their friends are, interview their friends,
know the quality of friends they have, even the ones you can ascertain that this one is good,
make sure you know the background of that friend so if anything goes wrong,
you know where to start from.
I think their friends are very paramount.
Please, parents, be watchful whom your children are friends with.
Praise the Lord!
Hallelujah! Viewers all over the world, you have heard it.
We also want to hear from Jeffery himself.
What advice do you have for viewers, particularly to youths who have the same habit
you had in the past.
Emmanuel! (God with us - Matthew 1:23)
My advice for the youth all over the world, having the same problem that I had
is to watch the kind of friends you keep.
There is a saying that show me your friends and I will tell you who you are.
It is so true.
You just have to watch the kind of friends you keep and the kind of movements you make.
It is not all friends who tell you something is good that is actually good;
they are there to deceive you.
The devil is real and he wants us to go down;
he doesn't want us to shine the way God wants us to shine.
My advice for you is believe in God because right now,
I am really happy being in the presence of the Lord.
I feel really...
Jeffery & Family - Morning Water Testimony
Words are not enough for him to explain how he is actually feeling right now.
So we thank God that God Almighty has used this medium of Morning Water to set you free.
The advice from Prophet T.B. Joshua is that you and your family
should go and make God's Word the standard for your lives
so that this kind of deliverance would remain permanent in your lives in Jesus' name.
Amen.